<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Robby Ardison&#39;s Webfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Robby Ardison&#39;s Webfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 12:43:55 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia&#39;s Earthquake Analysis</title>
      <link>/posts/indonesia_earthquake_eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 12:43:55 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/indonesia_earthquake_eda/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This analysis delves into a comprehensive exploration of earthquake data spanning the years 2011 to 2020. Through descriptive statistics, spatial and temporal analyses, and clustering techniques, we aim to uncover insights into the distribution, trends, and categorization of earthquakes in Indonesia. The findings provide valuable information for enhancing our understanding of earthquake occurrences, contributing to informed decision-making and strategic planning for seismic resilience in the region.&#xA;import numpy as np # Array handler import pandas as pd # Data analysis import seaborn as sns #Visualization import matplotlib.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Simple ETL Pipeline with Apache Airflow: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>/posts/airflow_etl_explanation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/airflow_etl_explanation/</guid>
      <description>Title: Building a Simple ETL Pipeline with Apache Airflow: A Step-by-Step Guide Introduction Apache Airflow is an open-source platform for orchestrating complex data workflows. In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll guide you through the process of building a simple ETL pipeline using Apache Airflow. Our example will focus on extracting data from a source, transforming it, and loading it into a destination.&#xA;Prerequisites Before you start, make sure you have Apache Airflow installed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Window Functions</title>
      <link>/posts/window_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/window_function/</guid>
      <description>Window Functions Documentation Window functions are a powerful feature in databases that allow you to perform calculations across a set of rows related to the current row. They are commonly used in SQL queries to analyze and aggregate data within a specific window or range.&#xA;Syntax The basic syntax for using window functions is as follows:&#xA;SELECT column1, column2, window_function(column3) OVER (PARTITION BY partition_column ORDER BY order_column ROWS BETWEEN N PRECEDING AND M FOLLOWING) AS result_column FROM your_table; window_function: The specific window function to be applied (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pandas Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>/posts/pandas_cheat_sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/pandas_cheat_sheet/</guid>
      <description>Pandas Cheat Sheet: A Comprehensive Guide to Data Manipulation in Python Pandas, a powerful and versatile library in Python, is the go-to tool for data manipulation and analysis. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a beginner or an experienced data scientist, this cheat sheet provides a quick reference for common Pandas operations, along with explanations and example codes.&#xA;Importing Pandas:&#xA;Explanation: Pandas is typically imported with the alias pd for brevity. Example Code: import pandas as pd Creating DataFrames:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netflix Stock Data</title>
      <link>/posts/netflix_visualizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/netflix_visualizations/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this project, you will act as a data visualization developer at Yahoo Finance! You will be helping the &amp;ldquo;Netflix Stock Profile&amp;rdquo; team visualize the Netflix stock data. In finance, a stock profile is a series of studies, visualizations, and analyses that dive into different aspects a publicly traded company&amp;rsquo;s data.&#xA;For the purposes of the project, you will only visualize data for the year of 2017. Specifically, you will be in charge of creating the following visualizations:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Favorite Book: 🏍️ The Motorcycle Diaries (1992) Favorite Film: 👨‍🍳 Chef (2014) Favorite TV Show: Ozark (2017-2022) Favorite Podcast: JRE, The Lex Fridman Podcast Favorite F1 Team: Ferrari Favorite Programmer: Linus Torvalds Favotie Youtuber: Linus Tech Tips Join me on this exciting journey of finding out the possibility of what could be. To quote Jeff Bezos, &amp;quot;Unlike the telescope which is an invention, A.I. is more of a discovery than an invention.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description> 📍 Jakarta, Indonesia ✉️ robby.ardison@hotmail.com 📞 +6281363917775 🔗 LinkedIn </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
